#### Get Started

#### Learn More

English

Get Started

Learn More

* English
* 中文
* Español
* Français
* Português
* Deutsch
* Nederlands
* Bahasa Indonesia
* Polski
* Norsk
* Naijá
* 日本語

Privacy Policy
==============

NANO FOUNDATION PRIVACY POLICY
------------------------------

If you need to see these details in another language, please contact us at [info@nano.org](mailto:info@nano.org) with the request.

### Introduction

Welcome to the Nano Foundation’s privacy policy.

Thank you for using our website, nano.org (the “Site”).

The Nano Foundation (NanoLabs Inc. trading as the Nano Foundation) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our Site (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

By using the Site you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Questions or comments may be addressed to: [info@nano.org](mailto:info@nano.org) .

### GDPR notice

When you are located inside the European Economic Area (currently comprised of the European Union countries, including the UK, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway) the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) also applies. The GDPR does not apply to any person, including citizens of EEA nations, who are located outside of the EEA.

If the GDPR applies to you then you have a number of important rights free of charge, which are set out in this policy.

This privacy policy is provided in a layered format so that you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy policy.

1. [Important information and who we are](#info-who-we-are)
2. [The data we collect about you](#data-collected-about-you)
3. [How is your personal data collected?](#personal-data-collected)
4. [How we use your personal data](#personal-data-use)
5. [Disclosures of your personal data](#disclosure-personal-data)
6. [Data security](#data-security)
7. [Data retention](#data-retention)
8. [Your GDPR legal rights](#gdpr-rights)
9. [Glossary](#glossary)

### 1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE

#### PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY

This privacy policy aims to give you information on how the Nano Foundation collects and processes your personal data through your use of this Site, nano.org, including any data you may provide through this Site at any time.

This Site is not intended for under 18 year olds and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy policy together with any other privacy policy or fair processing policy we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy policy supplements other notices and privacy policies and is not intended to override them.

#### CONTROLLER

The Nano Foundation is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “the Nano Foundation””, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy).

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ( [ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/) ). **We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.**

#### CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES

We keep our privacy policy under regular review.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

#### THIRD-PARTY LINKS

This Site, and other subdomain properties under nano.org (forum.nano.org, hub.nano.org, etc.), may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our Site, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

### 2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

1. **Identity Data**, for those who sign up to post into the Nano Forum, includes name and username.
2. **Contact Data** includes email address.
3. **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this Site\].
4. **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our Site, products and services including page views, routes taken through pages on the site and mouse movement within pages.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data will **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific Site feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

#### IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

### 3\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

* **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    * apply for our services;
    * create an account on our Site;
    * subscribe to our service or publications;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
    * give us feedback or contact us.
* **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our Site, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies.
* **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We will receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:

Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU.

### 4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

* Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
* Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

[Click here](#glossary) to find out more about the types of lawful basis that we will rely on to process your personal data.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data although we will get your consent before sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

| Purpose/Activity | Type of data | Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest |
| --- | --- | --- |
| To register you as a new publishing subscriber to the Nano forum | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact | Performance of a contract with you |
| To manage our relationship with you which will include:<br><br>(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy<br><br>(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation<br><br>(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) |
| To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Usage | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business) |
| To administer and protect our business and this Site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation |
| To deliver relevant Site content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Usage<br><br>(d) Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To use data analytics to improve our Site, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical<br><br>(b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our Site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical<br><br>(d) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business) |

#### MARKETING

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.

#### PROMOTIONAL OFFERS FROM US

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical and Usage to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us and you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

#### THIRD-PARTY MARKETING

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes.

#### OPTING OUT

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of signing up to the forum.

#### COOKIES

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when Sites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this Site may become inaccessible or not function properly. Below are details on the cookies being set on Nano.org sites:

Site: **nano.org**

| Cookie Name | Used By | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| nano-org-cookie-consent-agree | .nano.org | For tracking the acceptance of cookies on the site via a banner on the bottom of the site. |
| nano-org-activity-view | .nano.org | For storing the view preference on the News page. |
| \_\_cfduid  <br>  <br>uid  <br>  <br>nonce  <br>  <br>sid  <br>  <br>optimizelyEndUserId | .medium.com | For the content network CloudFlare, to identify trusted web traffic. |
| \_ga  <br>  <br>\_gat  <br>  <br>\_gid | .nano.org | For Google Analytics, used to gather information such as number of visitors to the website, which pages have been viewed and how long visitors stayed for. |
| 1P\_JAR  <br>ANID  <br>DV  <br>NID  <br>S  <br>OTZ  <br>OGPC  <br>SSID  <br>SAPISID  <br>\_Secure-\*  <br>SID  <br>SIDCC  <br>HSID  <br>APISID | .nano.org | For Google reCAPTCHA service for evaluating potential for bots on form submissions. |
| lidc  <br>lms\_analytics  <br>lms\_ads  <br>UserMatchHistory  <br>AnalyticsSyncHistory  <br>bcookie  <br>\_guid  <br>li\_sugr  <br>sdsc  <br>AMCVS\_\*  <br>lang  <br>U  <br>\_gcl\_au  <br>liap | .linkedin.com  <br>.adsymptotic.com | For analytics gathered from campaigns run on LinkedIn. See [LinkedIn's Cookie Table](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/l/cookie-table) for more details about the cookies. |

Site: **docs.nano.org**

| Cookie Name | Used By | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_\_cfduid | mathjax.org | For the content network CloudFlare, to identify trusted web traffic. |
| \_ga  <br>  <br>\_gat  <br>  <br>\_gid | .github.com  <br>  <br>docs.nano.org  <br>  <br>.nano.org | For Google Analytics, used to gather information such as number of visitors to the website, which pages have been viewed and how long visitors stayed for. |
| \_octo | .github.com | Used by GitHub Pages site host, distinguishes users and clients in Octolytics, GitHub’s internal analytics service. |
| logged\_in  <br>  <br>dotcom\_user | .github.com | Used by GitHub Pages site host, used to signal the user is logged into GitHub. |

Site: **forum.nano.org**

| Cookie Name | Used By | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_ga  <br>  <br>\_gat  <br>  <br>\_gid | forum.nano.org  <br>  <br>.nano.org | For Google Analytics, used to gather information such as number of visitors to the website, which pages have been viewed and how long visitors stayed for. |
| \_forum\_session  <br>\_t | forum.nano.org | For Discourse forum to track session details |

Site: **hub.nano.org**

| Cookie Name | Used By | Purpose |
| --- | --- | --- |
| \_ga  <br>  <br>\_gat  <br>  <br>\_gid | hub.nano.org  <br>  <br>.nano.org | For Google Analytics, used to gather information such as number of visitors to the website, which pages have been viewed and how long visitors stayed for. |
| nano-org-hub-cookie-consent-agree | hub.nano.org | For tracking the acceptance of cookies on the site via a banner on the bottom of the site. |
| nano-org-hub-cookie-popup-disclaimer-agree | hub.nano.org | For tracking the acceptance of the disclaimer about no responsiblity for behavior of [third-party sites and services](https://nano.org/terms#linked-websites). |
| nano-org-hub-theme | hub.nano.org | For persisting the preferred color theme on the Hub (dark or light). |

#### CHANGE OF PURPOSE

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### 5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may share your personal data with Third Parties (see Glossary) for the purposes set out in the table above.

We require all Third Parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### 6\. DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### 7\. DATA RETENTION

#### HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: [see below for further information](#gdpr-rights).

In some circumstances we will anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### 8\. YOUR GDPR LEGAL RIGHTS

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These rights include:

* Request access to your personal data.
* Request correction of your personal data.
* Request erasure of your personal data.
* Object to processing of your personal data.
* Request restriction of processing your personal data.
* Request transfer of your personal data.
* Right to withdraw consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

#### NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

#### WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

#### TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### 9\. GLOSSARY

#### LAWFUL BASIS

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation that we are subject to.

#### THIRD PARTIES

* Service providers who provide IT and system administration services.
* Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
* The Internal Revenue Service (IRS), HM Revenue & Customs (HMRC), regulators and other authorities who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.

#### YOUR GDPR LEGAL RIGHTS

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

* If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.
* Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.
* Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.
* You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

#### Get Started

#### Learn More

Nano Foundation is not responsible for the content of external sites. See the external links section of our Terms of Use.

© 2024 Nano Foundation. [Terms of Use](https://nano.org/en/terms). [Privacy Policy](https://nano.org/en/privacy).
